《星际迷航：无限太空》
作战
Tactical…
视像
Visual…
作战，准备发炮
Tactical, stand by on torpedoes.
准备…
Ready…
开火
Fire!
逃避
Evasive!
E9通讯站叫哥伦比亚号
This is comm station Epsilon IX, calling USS Columbia…
哥伦比亚号，请通话
Come in, Columbia. Respond, please…
这是E9，正在增强输出功率
This is Epsilon IX. Am boosting output…
你接收到吗？
How read you this?
侦察机哥伦比亚号，会合神圣号
Scout Columbia NCC-621 to rendezvous with Scout Revere NCC-595…
星际日期7411.4
On stardate 7411.4…
进一步指令将在这个时间转发
Further orders to be relayed at that time…
星际舰队普博指挥官示
Signed, Commodore Probert, Starfleet…
传讯完毕
End of transmission…
无法辨识入侵者 发光云雾应该是强大力场
Lntruder unidentified.
包围着异星太空船，无法扫描
Believe luminescent cloudto be enormous power fieldsurrounding alien vessel.
克林岗皇家巡洋舰 阿玛号继续攻击…
Our sensor scans unable to penetrate. lmperial Klingon Cruiser Amar, continuing to attack.
我方侦察机在L14区截听到这个
Our sensor drone is intercepting this on Quad I-1 4…
克林冈境内，他们在对抗什么？
That's within Klingon boundaries. Who are they fighting?
不知道，长官
Unknown, sir…
我有一个外界视像
I have an exterior visual…
我们已经标出那股星际云的航向
We've plotted a course on that cloud, Commander…
它会进入颇接近我们的联盟太空
It will pass into Federation space fairly close to us…
朝向哪里？
Heading?
长官，它正朝着地球前进
"Sir, it's on a precise heading for Earth…
我们的祖先在此摒弃他们的兽欲
Our ancestors cast out their animal passions here on these sands.
藉着高灵亚拯救我们的族人
Our race was saved by the attainment of Kolinahr.
透过高灵亚，一切情感都被抛弃
Kolinahr: through which all emotion is finally shed.
冼朴，你辛劳了很久
You have laboured long, Spock…
你也证明了自己有资格…接受我们这个纯逻辑的象征
Now receive from us this symbol of total logic.
把你的思想交给我
Your thoughts… give them to me.
我们的思想结合了，冼朴
Our minds, Spock…
合而为一
one and together…
我感觉到意识从太空召唤你
This consciousness calling to you from space…
你的人类血液被它触及了，冼朴
Lt touches your human blood, Spock.
你还没有达到高灵亚
You have not achieved Kolinahr.
他要到别处寻找他的答案
His answer lies elsewhere.
他不会在这里找到它的
He will not achieve his goal with us.
祝你长寿昌盛，冼朴
Live long and prosper, Spock.
（星舰总部 星际日期7410.2）
你被委任为企业号的科学员了？
Cmdr Sonak, you were appointed as Enterprise Science Officer?
- 根据你的推荐 - 你何不上船？
- Based on your recommendation. - Why aren't you aboard?
迪克队长叫我出发前做最后简报
Capt Decker requested I complete final briefing here before we leave…
在星际舰队？
At Starfleet?
企业号正在做出发前最后准备
The Enterprise is in final preparation to leave dock…
- 那需要二十小时 - 十二小时
- Which requires 20 hours. - 12…
我去见诺古拉司令，不会很久的
I'm meeting Admiral Nogura. I won't be more than three minutes…
一小时后在企业号上向我报到
Report to me on the Enterprise in one hour…
向你报到？
To you?
会议后我打算登上那艘太空船
It is my intention to be on that ship following that meeting…
一小时后向我报到
Report to me in one hour.
（办公室楼层）
- 司令 - 史葛先生
- Admiral. - Mr Scott…
十二小时后出发，不是认真的吧
Those departure orders, 12 hours. Starfleet cannot be serious…
为何那些输送器仍未操作？
Why aren't the transporters operating?
有个小问题，暂时性的
A wee problem. Temporary…
我们刚完成18个月的企业号改装
We have just finished 18 months' redesigning the Enterprise…
- 怎能12小时后出发 - 送我去吧
- How can she be ready in 12 hours? - Take me over, please…
她需要试航
She needs more work, a shakedown…
有一个杀伤力惊人的外来物体…
Mr Scott, an alien object of unbelievable destructive power…
不足三天就会来到地球
Is less than three days away from Earth…
在拦截范围内的飞船只有企业号
The only starship in interception range is the Enterprise…
无论如何，她要在12小时后发射
Ready or not, she launches in 12 hours…
船员没有足够时间熟习新仪器
The crew haven't had near enough time with all the new equipment…
而且引擎也未测试翘曲动力飞行
And the engines are not even tested at warp power…
还有一个不熟练的队长
And an untried captain…
我当了星际舰队行动总管两年半
Two and a half years as Chief of Starfleet Operations…
可能状态不佳，但并非不熟练
May have made me stale, but I wouldn't consider myself untried…
- 他们把她还给我 - 把她交还？
- They gave her back to me, Scotty. - Gave her back?
我怀疑诺古拉可会那么易商量
I doubt it was that easy with Nogura…
你说得对
You're right…
任何有这个能耐的人…
Well, any man who could manage such a feat…
我也不敢怠慢
I would not dare to disappoint…
长官，她会作好准备，依时出发
She'll launch on time, sir, and she'll be ready…
- 谢谢你 - 是，长官
- Thank you, Mr Scott. - Aye, sir…
货物站叫发射人员
Cargo bay to launch crew…
输送囊在六号船坞候命
Travel pod is now available at dock six…
- 请批准登船 - 批准，欢迎司令
- Permission to come aboard. - Granted. Welcome aboard, Admiral…
史葛指挥官，工程组找你
Cmdr Scott, you're needed in Engineering…
长官，失陪了
Sir, you'll excuse me…
飞行甲板，准备穿梭机进入
Flight deck, prepare for incoming shuttlecraft…
- 请跟我来… - 我识路的，安山
- If you'll follow me…- I think I can find my way, Ensign…
是，长官
Aye, sir…
驾驶台
Bridge…
我以为你一小时前接驳了线路
I thought you had that circuit patched in an hour ago…
是的，但我们要把它切断
We did. We had to disconnect it…
我会尽快找人去的
I'll get somebody there as soon as I can…
队长，星际舰队传来了指挥调动
Captain! Starfleet just signalled your transfer-of-command orders…
- 队长 - 谢谢大家欢迎
- Captain. - I appreciate the welcome…
但愿情况没有这么严重
I wish circumstances were less critical…
E9正监察入侵者，开启一条频道
Epsilon IX is monitoring the intruder. Keep a channel open…
迪克队长在哪里？
Where's Capt Decker?
他在工程部，他…不知道的
He's in Engineering, sir. He…doesn't know…
- 柴可夫先生 - 是，长官
- Mr Chekov. - Aye, sir…
叫船员0400小时在休憩甲板集合
Assemble the crew on the recreation deck at 0400 hours…
我要给他们展示我们要面对什么
I want to show them what we're facing…
奇里接受六号检查
Check Cleary on number six…
轮机室通告全舰 三分钟内测试辅助动力
Engine room informs the whole ship to test auxiliary power within 3 minutes.
我知道，输送机感应器失灵了
I knew it. The transporter sensor was not activated…
不完善的船舱
Faulty modules…
奇里，安装新的后备感应器进去
Cleary, put a new backup sensor into the unit…
葛克司令，我们有要员送别呢
Admiral Kirk. We're getting a top-brass sendoff…
我们即使要用手拖也要依时出发
She'll launch on schedule if we have to tow her with our hands. Right?
是，我们会的
Aye, that we will, sir…
- 我们谈一下 - 好的
- Let's talk. - Sure…
- 报告后备组件何时准备好 - 是
- Tell me when the backup's ready. - Aye, sir…
长官，我希望这不是打气的说话
Sir, I hope this isn't some kind of pep talk…
- 我很忙的 - 韦，我会接管
- I'm too busy. - I'm taking over, Will…
你什么？
You're what?
我会代替你做企业号的队长
I'm replacing you as Captain of the Enterprise…
你会继续留任做执行员
You'll stay on as Executive Officer…
暂时降职至指挥官
Temporary grade reduction to Commander…
你亲自执行指挥？
You personally are assuming command?
是的
Yeah…
我可否问原因？
May I ask why?
我曾经在太空对付不名物体五年
My experience. Five years out there dealing with unknowns like this…
我熟识企业号和它的船员
My familiarity with the Enterprise, its crew…
司令，这艘几乎全新的企业号
Admiral, this is an almost totally new Enterprise…
- 我更熟识它 - 所以你留在船上
- You don't know her like I do. - That's why you're staying aboard…
对不起，韦
I'm sorry, Will…
司令，我认为你完全没有歉意
No, Admiral, I don't think you're sorry, not one damn bit…
我记得你推荐我作指挥时
I remember when you recommended me for command…
你说多希望找到办法再指挥飞船
You said how much you hoped you'd find a way to get a starship again…
长官，看来你找到办法了
Well, sir, it looks like you found a way…
指挥官，马上到驾驶室报到
Report to the bridge, Commander, immediately…
是，长官
Aye, sir…
输送室，请通话
Transporter room. Come in…
输送器上出现了红线
Red line on the transporter…
- 别接合 - 太迟了，它们在发射
- Transporter, do not engage. - It's too late. They're beaming…
听到吗？撤销我们，把他们拉回
Do you read me, Starfleet? Override us. PulI them back…
不能撤回他们了，企业号
Unable to retrieve their pattern, Enterprise…
给我
Give it to me…
星际舰队，增强物体接收讯号
Starfleet, boost your matter gain. We need more signal…
要多一点讯号
More signal…
- 我们失去形状 - 他们在形成
- We're losing their pattern. - No, they're forming…
星际舰队，接收到他们吗？
Starfleet, do you have them?
企业号，我们接收到的东西死了
Enterprise, what we got back didn't live long, fortunately…
星际舰队，是葛克
Starfleet, Kirk…
请代我向他们的家人致哀
Please express my condolences to their families…
可以透过火神星大使馆接触桑尼
Cmdr Sonak's can be reached through the Vulcan Embassy…
兰，你没什么可以做的
There was nothing you could have done, Rand…
那不是你的错
It wasn't your fault…
- 涡轮发动机八号？- 在那边
- Yeoman, turboshaft eight? - Back that way, sir…
我想找个火神星人接替桑尼
We must replace Cmdr Sonak. I'd still like a Vulcan if possible…
没人对这设计是完全熟识的
None available, Captain. No one's fully rated on this design…
你熟识，你要兼当科学员
You are, Mr Decker. You'll have to double as Science Officer…
我们所知的只有这些
That's all we know about it…
除了它现在距离地球53.4小时
except that it is now 53.4 hours away from Earth…
企业号是唯一在它途中的飞船
Enterprise is the only Federation starship that stands in its way…
我们的任务是要拦截、 调查…
Our orders are to intercept, investigate…
和采取有必要及可行的行动
And take whatever action is necessary. And possible…
希望那个物体上有生命，了解我们的做法
We can only hope that there is a life form aboard that vessel…
驾驶室叫队长，E9有紧急讯号
Bridge to Captain. Priority signal from Epsilon IX…
- 传上视像器 - 知道
- Put it on viewer. - On viewer…
企业号，那股星云是某种强力场
Enterprise, the cloud is definitely a power field of some kind…
直径…我的天…有超过两埃
Measures…my God…over two AUs in diameter…
里面一定有种神奇的东西产生它
Must be something incredible inside there generating it…
我们正在各波段发放友好讯息
We're transmitting friendship messages on all frequencies…
- 没有回应 - 中心没有读数
- No response. - NulI reading at the centre…
里面没有东西，但扫描全被射回
There's something inside, but all scans are reflected back…
- 有动力上升 - 接收到个怪图像
- A power surge. - Receiving an odd pattern…
他们可能把我们的扫描视为敌意
They could be viewing our scans as a hostile act…
- 他们对扫描反应 - 导向器全速
- They're reacting to our scans. - Deflectors, fulI!
- 我们被袭击 - 外界情况视像
- We are under attack. - External view…
关闭视像器
Viewer off…
发射倒数在四十分钟后开始
Pre-launch countdown will commence in 40 minutes…
输送器系统完全修复和运作正常
Transporter system fully repaired and functioning, sir…
接合讯号清晰
Dock signals clear…
回覆我们正等候最后船员更换
Reply we are awaiting final crew replacements…
是，长官
Aye, sir…
输送员报告领航员是伊莉亚中尉
Transporter personnel reports the navigator It Ilia…
她已经登船，正前来驾驶室
She's already aboard and en route to the bridge, sir…
队长，她是德尔塔星人
She's Deltan, Captain…
- 长官，伊莉亚中尉报到 - 欢迎
- It Ilia reporting for duty, sir. - Welcome aboard, lieutenant…
- 你好，伊莉亚 - 迪克
- Hello, Ilia. - Decker…
我几年前驻守在中尉的星球
I was stationed on the lieutenant's home planet some years ago…
迪克指挥官？
Cmdr Decker?
我们的执行及科学员
Our Exec and Science Officer…
葛克队长对我有绝对信心
Capt Kirk has the utmost confidence in me…
对你也是，中尉
And in you too, lieutenant…
我已发禁欲誓言，可工作了吧？
My oath of celibacy is on record. May I assume my duties?
当然可以
By all means…
队长，最后六个船员准备输送
Captain, our last six crew members are ready to beam up…
但其中一个拒绝踏入输送器
But one of them is refusing to step into the transporter…
我去确保他进行输送，输送室
I'll see to it that he beams up. Transporter room…
你发誓永不回星际舰队的
And you swore never to return to Starfleet!
队长，等一等，我会解释
Just a moment, Captain, sir. I'll explain what happened…
你受敬重的诺古拉上将
Your revered Admiral Nogura…
实施鲜为人知的征用后备军条例
Invoked a little-known, seldom-used reserve activation clause…
简单而言，他们征召我入伍
In simpler language, Captain, they drafted me…
他们没有
They didn't…
这是你的主意，是不是？
This was your idea, wasn't it?
外面有一样东西
There's a thing out there…
任何我们不懂的物体都叫东西
Any object we don't understand is always a "thing"
朝着这方向来的，我需要你
Headed this way. I need you…
该死，邦斯，我很需要你
Damn it, Bones, I need you. Badly…
- 请批准登船 - 批准，长官
- Permission to come aboard? - Permission granted, sir…
占，听说卓普现在是医生了
Well, Jim, I hear Chapel's an MD now…
我需要一个高级护士
I'm going to need a top nurse…
不是个跟我争辩每个诊断的医生
Not a doctor who'll argue every diagnosis with me…
他们可能把整个医疗室也改装了
They probably redesigned the whole sickbay, too…
工程师们喜欢改动东西
Engineers love to change things…
船坞控制室说准备好了
Dock control reports ready, sir…
- 舵轮准备好了 - 出发轨道标定
- Helm ready, sir. - Orbital departure on plot, sir…
横杆指挥部示意妥当
Yard Command signalling clear, sir…
- 控制推进器 - 控制推进器
- Manoeuvring thrusters, Mr Sulu. - Manoeuvring thrusters…
定位
Hold station…
推进器已经定位
Thrusters at station-keeping, sir…
苏洛先生，推进器前进
Thrusters ahead, Mr Sulu…
出发
Take us out…
设定混合模式，你可用脉冲动力
Intermix set, bridge. Impulse power at your discretion…
推进动力，苏洛先生
Impulse power, Mr Sulu…
前进，翘曲度五级
Ahead, warp point five…
- 显示起飞角度视像 - 起飞角度
- Departure angle on viewer. - Departure angle…
显示前方视像
Viewer ahead…
星际日期7412.6发射后1.8小时
Captain's log, stardate 7412.6, 1.8 hours from launch…
为了尽快拦截入侵者
In order to intercept the intruder at the earliest possible time…
我们在太阳系中冒险作翘曲飞行
We must risk engaging warp drive while still within the solar system…
假设我们完全有翘曲飞行性能
Captain, assuming we have fulI warp capability…
在太阳系外加速至翘曲度第七级
Accelerating to warp seven outside the solar system…
会让我们在20.1小时拦截入侵者
Will bring us to IP with the intruder in 20.1 hours…
科学员计算确认
Science officer's computation confirmed, sir.
邦斯，你满意那些新设备吗？
Bones, do the new facilities meet with your approval?
不满意，像在电脑中心工作似的
They do not. It's like working in a computer centre…
- 程式准备了 - 调校作翘曲飞行
- Programming ready? - Set for warp entry…
但我仍提议作进一步模拟研究
But I still recommend further simulation study…
那物体每过一分钟就更接近地球
Mr Decker, every minute brings that object closer to Earth…
工程人员，准备作翘曲推进
Engineering, stand by for warp drive…
我们还要进一步模拟流动感应器
We need further simulation on flow sensors…
工程师，我们现在要翘曲速度
Engineer, we need warp speed now…
占，你在咄咄逼人
Jim, you're pushing…
你的下属明白他们的工作
Your people know their jobs…
- 就这样，我已尽了力 - 是的
- That's it. I can't do any better. - Aye, lad…
模拟器勉强可行，我不能保证
It's borderline on the simulator. I cannot guarantee she'll hold up…
翘曲推进 翘曲度一级前进
Warp drive, Mr Scott. Ahead, warp one, Mr Sulu…
加速至翘曲度一级
Accelerating to warp one, sir…
翘曲度七级…八级
Warp point seven…point eight…
翘曲度一级
Warp one, sir…
迪克先生
Mr Decker…
蠕虫洞
Wormhole…
全速调回用脉冲动力
Get us back on impulse power. FulI reverse…
舵轮控制失效，调回用脉冲动力
Negative helm control. Going reverse on impulse power…
子空间频率被干扰，蠕虫洞效应
Subspace frequencies jammed, sir. Wormhole effect…
控制失效会持续22.5秒
Negative control will continue 22.5 seconds…
然后会减至负光速度
Before velocity slows to sublight speed…
前面的蠕虫洞里有不明小型物体
Unidentified small object is in the wormhole with us, directly ahead…
张开障碍力场，视像器显示物件
Force fields up fulI. Put object on viewer…
人手操控舵轮
Manual override on helm…
- 没有反应 - 准备导航器
- No manual response. - Navigational deflectors coming up…
畸变令动力系统负荷过量
Distortion has overloaded power systems…
导航器失灵了
Navigational deflectors inoperative…
方向控制仪也失灵
Directional control also inoperative…
- 撞击时间？- 二十秒
- Time to impact? - 20 seconds…
柴可夫先生，准备突变仪
Mr Chekov, stand by on phasers…
不
No…
延迟那个突变仪的命令
Belay that phaser order…
准备光子炮
Arm photon torpedoes…
光子炮…
Photon torpedoes…
准备好了
…armed…
目标是个小行星，质量读数七级
Object is an asteroid. Reading mass point seven…
瞄准小行星
Targeting asteroid…
十秒内撞击
Impact in ten seconds…
八秒内撞击
Impact in eight seconds…
发炮
Fire torpedoes…
- 六秒 - 已经发炮
- Six. - Torpedoes away…
四秒
Four…
舵轮控制恢复了
Helm control restored, sir…
- 报告位置 - 计算新的交叉航道
- Position report, Navigator. - Computing new intersection course…
- 通讯正常 - 无损毁报告，队长
- Communications normal. - Negative damage reported, Captain…
医生，无受伤报告
No casualties reported, Doctor…
错，有受伤，是我的神智
Wrong, Mr Chekov. There are casualties. My wits…
正如「受惊吓」，队长
As in "frightened out of", Captain, sir…
我们在翘曲度八级，报告情况
We're at warp point eight. Engineer, report your status there…
等一等，我们正在了解情况
Just a second. We're picking up the pieces down here…
史葛先生，我们要翘曲推进
Mr Scott, we need warp drive…
有个引擎失调造成那个蠕虫洞
An engine imbalance created the wormhole in the first place…
我们要矫正它
We must correct it…
那物体离地球不足两天，要拦截
That object is less than two days from Earth. We must intercept it…
领航员，设定新航导配合拦截点
Navigator, lay in a new heading to conform with our initial IP…
苏洛先生，你暂代指挥
Mr Sulu, you have the conn…
迪克先生，到我的舱房见我
Mr Decker, I'd like to see you in my quarters…
介意我跟着来吗，队长？
Mind if I tag along, Captain?
五楼
Level five.
解释为何要收回我的突变仪命令
Explanation. Why was my phaser order countermanded?
改装了的企业号透过它的主引擎
The Enterprise redesign increases phaser power…
可以增强突变动力
By channelling it through the main engines…
当它们出现反物质不平衡时
When they went into antimatter imbalance…
那些突变仪就自动切断了
The phasers were automatically cut off…
当然你做得很对
You acted properly, of course…
过奖，长官
Thank you, sir…
抱歉若果我令你尴尬
I'm sorry if I embarrassed you…
- 你拯救了飞船 - 我明白，长官
- You saved the ship. - I'm aware of that, sir…
别再和我竞争，迪克
Stop competing with me, Decker…
- 请求批准直言 - 批准
- Permission to speak freely? - Granted…
你两年半来没有作过星际飞行
You haven't logged a single star hour in two and a half years…
加上你不熟识这艘飞船的新设计
That, plus your unfamiliarity with the ship's redesign…
我认为会严重危害这次任务
In my opinion, seriously jeopardises this mission…
我相信你会协助我解决这些困难
I trust you will… nursemaid me through these difficulties, mister?
是，长官，我会的
Yes, sir, I'll do that…
那么我不阻延你执行任务了
Then I won't keep you from your duties any longer…
- 是，医生？- 长官
- Yes, Doctor? - Aye, sir…
占，他可能是对的
He may be right, Jim…
很难应付？
Was it difficult?
我早料到，像重遇你般难应付
No more than I expected. About as difficult as seeing you again…
- 抱歉 - 因你离开德尔塔四号？
- I'm sorry. - That you left Delta IV?
还是你不辞而别？
Or that you didn't even say goodbye?
若果当时我再遇上你
If I had seen you again…
你说得出再见吗？
.. would you have been able to say it?
不能
No…
说吧，医生
Make your point, Doctor…
我认为你在跟自己竞争
The point is it is you who's competing…
你强行向星际舰队得到这次指挥
You rammed getting this command down Starfleet's throat…
你利用这次紧急事件得回企业号
You've used this emergency to get the Enterprise back…
而我打算保留她，是不是？
And I intend to keep her, is that it?
是
Yes…
这是一种迷恋
It's an obsession…
可以蒙蔽你处理更紧急的职责
An obsession that can blind you to more critical responsibilities…
你对迪克的反应就是个例子
Your reaction to Decker is an example, Jim…
驾驶室叫队长
Bridge to Captain…
开启视像器
Viewer on…
一艘联盟登记的远程穿梭机发讯
Signal from a Federation-registered long-range shuttle…
希望飞到我们旁边和锁上
She wishes to come alongside and lock on…
为什么？
For what purpose?
保安扫描显示它有一级特权
Security scan shows it has a grade-one priority, Captain…
确认属非交战身份
Non-belligerency confirmed…
我怀疑它是某种信使
I suspect it is a courier of some kind…
好的，柴可夫先生，去看着
Very well, Mr Chekov. See to it…
关掉视像器
Viewer off…
你的意见听过了，还有什么？
Your opinion has been noted. Anything further?
那要视乎你了
That depends on you…
有登船者，非活跃星际舰队人员
Security scan. One boarder. Identity, Starfleet inactive…
长官，要求批准登船
Permission to come aboard, sir…
批准，长官
Granted, sir…
- 为什么…是… - 冼朴！
- Why… it's Mr… - Spock!
指挥官，我可以吗？
Commander, if I may?
可否…
If…
我监察过你跟星际舰队的通讯
I monitored your communications with Starfleet, Captain…
我知道你们的引擎设计有困难
I'm aware of your engine-design difficulties…
我愿意当科学员
I offer my services as Science Officer…
恕我冒犯，指挥官
With all due respect, Commander…
我们的执行员不反对吧？
Our Exec has no objections?
不反对，我知道冼朴先生的资格
No. I know Mr Spock's qualifications…
柴可夫先生，重编冼朴先生入队
Mr Chekov, log Mr Spock's Starfleet commission reactivated…
编他做科学员
List him as Science Officer…
两个…立刻生效
Both…effective immediately…
冼朴先生！
Mr Spock!
来帮我吧，我很高兴见到你
Well, so help me, I'm actually pleased to see you…
- 我们都是 - 队长你容许的话…
- It's how we all feel. - Captain, with your permission…
我去跟工程师讨论燃料方程式
I will discuss fuel equations with the Engineer…
冼朴先生
Mr Spock…
欢迎上船
Welcome aboard…
队长日志，星际日期7413.4
Captain's log, stardate 7413.4…
幸得冼朴先生及时到来相助
Thanks to Mr Spock's timely arrival and assistance…
我们使引擎恢复至翘曲全功能
We have the engines rebalanced into fulI warp capacity…
修理时间不足三小时
Repair time less than three hours…
我们距离地球一天多…
We will be able to intercept intruder…
仍可以拦截到入侵者
While still more than a day from Earth…
翘曲度八级
Warp, point eight…
九级
Point nine…
二级
Warp two…
三级
Warp three…
四级
Warp four…
五级
Warp five…
六级
Warp six…
七级，长官
Warp seven, sir…
科学员应召报到
Science Officer Spock reporting as ordered…
请坐
Please, sit down…
你一点也没有改变
You haven't changed a bit…
你跟从前一样友善合群
You're just as warm and sociable as ever…
你也没有改变
Nor have you…
你偏爱离题万丈的言词
As your predilection for irrelevancy demonstrates…
两位
Gentlemen…
最后报告说你留在火神星的
At last report, you were on Vulcan. Apparently to stay…
对，你要接受高灵亚的训练
Yes, you were undergoing the Kolineer discipline…
坐下
Sit down…
如果你指的是高灵亚，你是对的
If you are referring to the Kolinahr, Doctor, you are correct…
叫什么也好吧
Well, however it's pronounced, Mr Spock…
它是驱走所有情感的火神星仪式
It's the Vulcan ritual supposed to purge all remaining emotions…
你违抗了高灵亚的纪律来找我们
The Kolinahr is also a discipline you broke…to join us…
你坐下来好吗？
Will you, please… sit down?
我在火神星感到一股强大意识
On Vulcan, I began sensing a consciousness…
是我从来没感觉过的
More powerful than I have ever encountered…
是绝对完好的思想模式
Thought patterns of exactingly perfect order…
我相信是那入侵者发射的
I believe they emanate from the intruder…
我相信它掌握着我的答案
I believe it may hold my answers…
我们朝你而来是不是很幸福？
Well, isn't it Iucky for you that we're heading your way?
邦斯！
Bones!
我们需要他
We need him…
我需要他
I need him…
那么我的出现对我们双方都有利
Then my presence is to our mutual advantage…
你感应到任何思想模式…
Any thought patterns you might sense…
不管影响你与否，马上向我报告
whether they affect you or not, I expect immediately reported…
好的，队长
Of course, Captain…
还有别的事吗？
Is there anything else?
没有
No…
占？
Jim?
如果这种超级智慧对他这么重要
If this super intelligence is as important to him as he says…
我们怎么知道？
How do we know?
他不会置他的利益于飞船之上？
That he wouldn't put his own interests ahead of the ship's?
我相信不会是那样的
I could never believe that…
重估星云出现时间，3.7分钟
Revised estimate on cloud visual contact. 3. 7 minutes…
我来了
On my way…
警报状况 红色
Red alert…
标准光度，工程师
Standard light, Engineer…
- 放大视像 - 放大了
- FulI mag on viewer. - FulI mag, sir…
语言吗？
Linguacode?
所有频率都是友善讯息
Friendship messages on all frequencies…
所有舱房确认，红色状态
All decks confirmed. Status red…
队长，我们被扫描
Captain, we are being scanned…
别回应，可能会被视为敌意
Do not return scan. It could be misinterpreted as hostility…
从星云中心发出的入侵者扫描
Intruder scans emanating from the exact centre of the cloud…
一种从未接触过的能量
Energy of a type never before encountered…
讯息没有回应
No response to messages…
- 战机？- 不是，没有挑衅行动
- Battle stations? - Negative. No provocative action…
建议作防御措施，庇护屏障
Recommend defensive posture. Screens and shields…
不，那可能也会被视为敌意
No, Mr Decker, that could also be misinterpreted as hostile…
冼朴先生，星云结构？
Cloud composition, Mr Spock?
- 第十二级能量场 - 第十二级？
- Twelfth-power energy field. - Twelfth?
我们见过他们的威力，要作防备
We've seen what they can do. We should take precautions…
我怀疑那星云的中心有一个物件
I suspect there's an object at the heart of that cloud…
我不会挑起侵袭，如果不清楚…
I will not provoke an attack. If that isn't clear…
作为执行员，我有责任提出办法
As your Exec, it's my duty to point out alternatives…
是的，我同意
Yes, it is. I stand corrected…
五分钟后到达星云边界
Five minutes to cloud boundary…
设定圆锥曲线航道进入星云中心
Navigator, lay in a conic section flight path to cloud centre…
在里面发现什么就跟它并行
Bring us parallel to whatever we find in there…
- 苏洛，显示战术图像 - 知道
- Mr Sulu, tactical plot on viewer. - On viewer…
它有第十二级能量？
That measures twelfth-power energy?
几千艘飞船也产生不到那么多
Thousands of starships couldn't generate that much…
冼朴，告诉我
Spock, tell me…
我感应到…困惑
I sense…puzzlement…
我们被接触过
We have been contacted…
为何我们不回应？
Why have we not replied?
被接触过？怎样？
Contacted? How?
张开力场！导向器，快点！
Force fields up fulI! Deflectors, now!
力场和导向器就位，队长
Force fields and deflectors up fulI, Captain…
分析，冼朴先生
Analysis, Mr Spock…
外来武器是一种等离子体能量
Alien weapon is a form of plasma energy…
结构不明，导航系统不明
Exact composition unknown. Guidance system unknown…
所有舱面准备迎击
All decks brace for impact…
- 工程组报告 - 系统负荷过量
- Engineering, status report. - Systems overloading…
- 急救员 - 急救员快来了
- Medic. - Medics are coming…
屏幕好了
The new screens held.
工程组叫驾驶室
Engineering to bridge…
维持不到力场最高动力
Cannot hold fulI power on force field…
导向器动力下降了百分之七十！
Deflector power is down 70 percent!
转移辅助动力引导向器
Divert auxiliary power to deflectors…
队长，入侵者一直在尝试通讯
Captain, the intruder has been attempting to communicate…
以这个速度，信息只维持一毫秒
At such speed, their entire message lasts only a millisecond…
我会设定我们的电脑
I will program our computer to transmit linguacode…
以他们的频率和速度传送语言码
At their frequency and rate of speed…
指挥官
Commander…
冼朴！
Spock!
- 它来了 - 我们的力场怎样？
- Here it comes. - How is our force field?
我们的屏障应付不到另一次袭击
Our shields cannot handle another attack!
冼朴先生？
Mr Spock?
二十秒
Twerty seconds…
- 冼朴 - 十五秒
- Spock. - 15 seconds…
冼朴，快传送！
Spock, transmit now!
十秒
Ten seconds…
传送中
Transmitting…
看来我们的信息已被接收和理解
It would seem our messages have been received and understood…
只有纯逻辑
only pure logic…
- 苏洛，保持现在位置 - 知道
- Mr Sulu, hold present position. - Holding position, sir…
- 战术图像 - 显示作战航道
- Tactical plot on viewer. - Course projection on tactical, sir…
- 冼朴先生，意见 - 建议进行
- Opinion, Mr Spock. - Recommend we proceed…
迪克先生？
Mr Decker?
我建议防备，我们再抵不住袭击
I advise caution. We can't withstand another attack…
那来历不明的东西离地球20小时
That thing is 20 hours from Earth. We know nothing about it…
正是，我们不知道它会做什么
Precisely the point. We don't know what it'll do…
现在进入那星云是不必要的冒险
Moving into that cloud at this time is an unwarranted gamble…
你怎么界定「不必要」？
How do you define "unwarranted"?
你问我的意见的，长官
You asked my opinion, sir…
视像器，显示前方
Viewer, standard ahead…
领航员，保持航向，舵手，靠稳
Navigator, maintain course. Helmsman, steady as she goes…
没有飞船能产生这么大的动力场
No vessel could generate a power field of this magnitude…
队长，仪器不稳定
Instruments fIuctuating, Captain…
模式不明
Patterns unrecognisable…
传送影像到星际舰队，尝试通讯
Transmit image to Starfleet. Attempt communication…
联络不到星际舰队
Unable to make contact with Starfleet…
所有从星云传送的信息都被射回
Any attempt to transmit out of the cloud is being reflected back…
队长，我们迅速靠近它了
We're closing on it rapidly, Captain…
苏洛先生，把放大量降至四级
Reduce magnification factor four, Mr Sulu…
我们已经降至两级以下了
We're already two settings below that…
苏洛先生，驶进并行航道
Mr Sulu…bring us into a parallel course…
在外星人上五百米
Over the alien at 500 metres…
五百米？
500 metres?
驶出一百公里，调整并行航道
Then take us out to 100 kilometres, adjusting parallel course…
知道
Aye, sir…
- 船尾视像 - 调转视像角度
- Viewer astern. - Reverse angle on the viewer…
五百米
500 metres…
视像显示前方
Viewer ahead, sir…
保持双对位置在这里
Hold relative position here…
冼朴先生
Mr Spock!
那可会是他们的船员之一？
Can that be one of their crew?
是他们飞船的探测器
A probe from their vessel, Captain…
等离子体能量组合
Plasma-energy combination…
别干扰它！
Don't interfere with it!
当然，我不会干扰的！
Absolutely, I will not interfere!
谁也不得干扰
No one interfere…
它看来只对这艘飞船感兴趣
It doesn't seem interested in us, only the ship…
关掉电脑
Computer off…
它控制了电脑
It's taken control of the computer!
它在检视我们的记录，地球防卫
It's running our records. Earth defences. Starfleet strength…
伊莉亚
Ilia!
这就是我说的「不必要」！
This is how I define "unwarranted"!
经人手关闭，启动辅助电脑线路
Activate auxiliary computer circuits through manual shut-off…
大家坐稳了，准备转向
Emergency Alert! Negative control at helm!
飞船受到攻击，被吸过去了
Force fields! Full remaining strength! Total reserve!
我们被一股光束袭击
We have been seized by a tractor beam…
找人接上领航员的岗位
Someone take the Navigator's station…
- 用紧急动力 - 迪费高到驾驶室
- Engineering, emergency power. - DiFalco to bridge…
若我们15秒内不脱离就会燃烧
Captain, if we don't break free in 15 seconds, she'll burn up!
办不到，我们只有少量的动力
We cannot break free. We have only a fraction of the power necessary…
工程组，延续命令切断主推进器
Engineering, belay that order. Disengage main drive systems…
迪费高总管，接管伊莉亚的岗位
Chief DiFalco, take over It Ilia's station…
迪费高，切断机械导航继电器
DiFalco, disengage engine navigation relays now…
E10至14力场线路准备重新启动
Force field circuits E10 through 14 show ready for reactivation…
请确认
Confirm, please…
史葛，推进系统应该脱离
Scotty, drive systems should be free…
- 指挥官 - 准备发射遥控侦察机
- Commander. - Ready to launch remote drone…
机上有本船记录，包括目前情况
With ship's records, incIuding our present situation…
别发射，我们被困侦察机逃不了
Delay launch. Our drone can't escape as long as we're held…
知道
Aye…
队长…
Captain…
用高度突变袭击可助我们脱身
A maximum phaser strike might weaken it enough for us to break free…
脱身去哪里？
Break free to where?
任何反抗都会无效
Any show of resistance would be futile…
我们不知道，为何你反对尝试？
We don't know that, Mr Spock. Why are you opposed to trying?
为何要引我们进去？
Why bring us inside?
他们早就可以在外面摧毁我们
Not to destroy us. They could have done that outside…
他们仍然可以
They still can…
是好奇心，迪克先生
Curiosity, Mr Decker…
无法满足的好奇心
Insatiable curiosity…
光声纳读数显示孔径快将关闭
Captain, photic sonar readings indicate the aperture is closing…
长官，我们被困了
We're trapped, sir…
调转视像角度
Reverse angle on the viewer…
队长，光束把我们释放了
Tractor beam has released us, Captain…
确认飞船在悬浮，没有前进动力
Confirmed. Vessel is floating free. No forward momentum…
视像显示前方
Viewer ahead…
苏洛先生，推进器前进三分之一
Manoeuvring thrusters, Mr Sulu. Ahead one third…
推进器前进三分之一
Thrusters ahead one third…
冼朴先生，启动感应扫描
Let's take a look. FulI sensor scan, Mr Spock…
他们该料到我们会扫描他们
They can't expect us not to scan them now…
我们往他们的喉咙看下去
We're looking down their throat…
我们在他们预料的位置中了
We've got them just where they want us…
它在关闭
It's closing up…
保持位置
Hold position…
队长
Captain…
我们所有扫描都被射回
All our scans are being reflected back…
- 感应器都是没用的 - 该死！
- Sensors are useless. - Damn!
你认为这是什么？
What do you make of this?
那关上的洞口是通往另一个室的
I believe the closed orifice leads to another chamber…
肯定是这艘飞船部分的内部结构
Undoubtedly, part of the vessel's inner mechanism…
我怀疑可能需要…
I suspect it may be necessary…
入侵者警报！机组人员舱房
Intruder alert! Officers' quarters…
叫保安组到升降舵见我
Have Security meet me at the elevator…
冼朴，迪克你来指挥，保持位置
Spock. Mr Decker, you have the conn. Hold position…
你就是葛克组件，你要协助我
You are the Kirk unit. You will assist me…
我受「威者」程式来观察和记录
I've been programmed by V'Ger to observe and record…
侵扰企业号的碳化组件平常功能
Normal functions of the carbon-based units infesting USS Enterprise…
- 占，什么事？- 三维录像器
- Jim, what's going on? - Tricorder…
谁是…
Who is…
「威者」 ？
.. V'Ger?
我的程式就是威者输入的
V'Ger is that which programmed me…
威者是那艘飞船的船长名字？
Is V'Ger the name of the captain of the alien vessel?
占，这是个机械人
Jim, this is a mechanism!
一个探测器
A probe, Captain…
肯定是个感应收发组合
No doubt, a sensor-transceiver combination…
记录我们所说和所做的一切
Recording everything we say and do…
- 伊莉亚在哪？- 那组件失效了
- Where's It Ilia? - That unit no longer functions…
我以它的形体跟侵扰企业号的…
I've been given its form to talk with the carbon-based units…
碳化组件交谈
Infesting Enterprise…
碳化组件？
Carbon-based units?
人类，安山佩雷斯，我们
Humans, Ensign Perez. Us…
为何威者要去太阳系的第三行星
Why does V'Ger travel to the third planet of the solar system ahead?
为了寻找创造者
To find the Creator…
什么？创造者？
What? Creator?
谁的？
Whose?
威者要创造者做什么？
What does V'Ger want with the Creator?
- 和他结合 - 和他结合？怎样？
- To join with him. - To join with the Creator? How?
威者和创造者会合而为一
V'Ger and the Creator will become one…
创造者是谁？
Who is the Creator?
创造者是创造威者的
The Creator is that which created V'Ger…
- 威者是谁？- 威者搜寻创造者
- Who is V'Ger? - That which seeks the Creator…
我准备开始进行我的观察
I'm ready to commence my observations…
检验这个探测器
An examination of this probe…
可能探究到它由谁制造
Might provide insight into those who manufactured it…
- 和怎样应付他们 - 好的
- And how to deal with them. - Fine…
带她到医疗室
Let's get her to sickbay…
我的程式只是作观察和记录…
I'm programmed to observe and record…
碳化组件的平常功能
Only the normal functioning of the carbon units…
这个检验是平常功能
The…examination is a normal function…
你可以进行
You may proceed…
超小型液压
Micro-miniature hydraulics…
感应器
Sensors…
还有微型多重处理晶片
And molecule-sized multiprocessor chips…
- 看这个 - 微型渗透泵，这里
- And take a look at this. - Osmotic micro-pump. Right here…
最微小的身体机能也复制了出来
Even the smallest body functions are exactly duplicated…
所有外分泌系统也是一样
Every exocrine system is the same, too…
甚至有眼水
Even eye moisture…
奇妙，竟然不是叫「迪克组件」
Fascinating. Not "Decker unit"
各位
Gentlemen…
韦
Will…
- 她发生了什么事？- 队长
- What happened to her? - Captain…
这探测器或是追查外星人的关键
This probe may be our key to the aliens…
- 探测器？伊莉亚？- 对
- Probe? Ilia? - Exactly…
它是一个被编了程式的机器
It is a programmed mechanism…
它精确复制我们的领航员的身体
Its body duplicates our Navigator in precise detail…
假若在它的程式当中
Suppose that beneath its programming…
伊莉亚的记忆也同样被精确复制
Ilia's memory patterns are duplicated with equal precision…
- 他们有一个模式可跟随 - 对
- They had a pattern to follow. - Indeed…
他们可能跟得太精确了
They may have followed it too precisely…
伊莉亚的记忆、 忠心服从、 友情
Ilia's memory, her feelings of loyalty, obedience, friendship…
可能都在里面
Might all be there!
你跟伊莉亚曾经有一段情
You did have a relationship with It Ilia…
就是那模仿的探测器杀死伊莉亚
That probe in another form is what killed Ilia!
指挥官！
Commander!
我们被困在一艘外星人飞船内
Will. We're locked in an alien vessel six hours from Earth…
那探测器是与俘虏者唯一的接触
Our only contact with our captor is that probe…
如果我们可以控制它，利用它…
If we could control it, use it…
我记录够了，你们要再协助我
I have recorded enough here. You will now assist me further…
迪克组件可以更有效地协助你的
The Decker unit can assist you with much greater efficiency…
迪克先生，执行你的任务吧
Carry on with your assignment, Mr Decker…
是，长官
Aye, sir…
我担心那是我们唯一的资料来源
I am concerned with that being our only source of information…
队长日志，星际日期7414.1
Captain's log, stardate 7414.1…
我们最乐观估计距离地球四小时
Our best estimates place us four hours from Earth…
目前仍未有重大进展
No significant progress thus far…
在探测器体内还原伊莉亚的记忆
Reviving Ilia memory patterns within the alien probe…
我们仍只有这个方法联络俘虏者
This remains our only means of contact with our captor…
这些飞船都是叫做企业号
All those vessels were called Enterprise…
那些碳化组件在这个范围消遣的
The carbon units use this area for recreation…
这是其中一种游戏
This is one of the games…
你们的船员喜欢什么消遣？
What types of recreation does the crew aboard your vessel enjoy?
「消遣」和「喜欢」这些字眼
The words "recreation" and "enjoy"…
在我的程式中没有意思
Have no meaning to my programming…
伊莉亚喜欢玩这个游戏
Ilia enjoyed this game…
她经常赢的
She nearly always won…
很好，他在利用视听联系
Good. He's using audio-visual association…
这个装置没有用途
This device serves no purpose…
为何企业号要有碳化组件在船上
Why does Enterprise require the presence of carbon units?
没有他们，企业号不能运作
Enterprise could not function without them…
要有更多关于这个功能的资料
More data concerning this functioning is necessary…
碳化组件才能用作储存资料
Before carbon units can be patterned for data storage…
什么意思？
What does that mean?
我的检验完成之后…
When my examination is complete…
所有碳化组件都会缩成资料模式
All carbon units will be reduced to data patterns…
你体内有某个碳化组件的…
Within you are the memory patterns of…
记忆模式
A certain carbon unit…
若我能帮你还原那些模式
If I can help you to revive those patterns…
你就可以更了解我们的功能
You could understand our functions better…
这很合逻辑，你可以进行
That is logical. You may proceed…
我记得伊莉亚提过她戴这个
I remember It Ilia once mentioning she wore that…
在德尔塔星，记得吗？
On Delta. Remember?
伊莉亚？
Ilia?
卓普医生
Dr Chapel…
韦？
Will?
伊莉亚
Ilia…
指挥官
Commander…
这是一副机器
This is a mechanism…
伊莉亚，帮我们直接联络威者吧
Ilia, help us make direct contact with V'Ger…
我不可以
I cannot…
威者找的创造者是什么？
This Creator V'Ger's looking for. What is it?
威者不知道
V'Ger does not know…
电脑，开始记录
Computer, commence recording…
葛克队长，这些信息会详细记下
Capt Kirk, these messages will detail my attempt…
我尝试接触外星人的情况
To contact the aliens…
警告，紧急逃离推进器已装备
Warning! Your emergency evacuation thruster pack has been armed.
点火后推进时间10秒 按点火钮后开始倒计时
Once ignited, the burn duration is 10 seconds and may not be aborted.
打开把手可除去装置
Push the igniter-enable release to begin a 10-second countdown…
我会计算加速程度
I intend to calculate acceleration rate…
去配合那个威者洞口的开启
To coincide with the opening of the V'Ger orifice…
这样该有助看清楚内部
This should facilitate a better view of the interior…
长官，星际舰队的讯号越来越强
Starfleet signals are growing in strength, sir…
他们仍监察到那个入侵者
They still have the intruder on their monitors…
- 它正在减速 - 确定
- It's decelerating. - Confirmed…
月球信标显示入侵者入地球轨道
Iunar beacons indicate intruder on a course into Earth orbit…
四号气窝开了，一件推进衣失踪
Sir, airlock four has been opened. A thruster suit is reported missing…
一件推进衣？
A thruster suit?
是冼朴
That's Spock…
他该死！把他带回来
Damn him! Bring him back here…
不，等一等
No, wait…
- 找出他的位置 - 是，长官
- Get a fix on his position. - Aye, sir.
（武器装置）
（开动发射器）
（发射）
我已穿过外星人内部的另一个室
I have penetrated the next chamber of the alien's interior…
我看见某种立体影像
I'm witnessing some sort of dimensional image…
我相信是代表威者的原居行星
Which I believe is a representation of V'Ger's home planet…
我正通过一条连接的隧道
I'm passing through a connecting tunnel…
看来是一种等离子体能量管道
Apparently a kind of plasma-energy conduit…
可能是个巨型影响系统的场线圈
Possibly, a field coil for a gigantic imaging system…
奇怪，我看见行星、 月亮、 星宿
Curious. I'm seeing images of planets. Moons. Stars…
整个银河系被储存和记录起来
Whole galaxies stored, recorded…
这可能代表了威者的整个旅程
It may be a representation of V'Ger's entire journey…
但我们要应付的是谁或是什么？
But who or what are we dealing with?
E9太空站被详细地储存在这里
The Epsilon IX station, stored here with every detail…
队长，我相信这一切就是威者
Captain, I am now quite convinced that all of this is V'Ger…
我们在一副活的机器里
That we are inside a living machine…
那个感应器一定有特别用意
The sensor…must contain some special meaning…
我要尝试和它融合意识
I must try to mind-meld with it…
现在扫描脊骨神经纤维连接范围
Now scanning pons area. Spinal nerve fibre connection…
显示有一些神经性创伤
Indications of some neurological trauma…
撞击那意识融合的动力一定很大
The power pouring through that mind-meld must have been staggering…
- 我知道 - 你对威者的看法对吗
- I should have known. - Were you right? About V'Ger?
一个有知觉的活体
A life form of its own. A conscious, living entity…
一副活机器？
A living machine?
它视企业号为一副活机器
It considers the Enterprise a living machine…
我看见威者的行星
I saw V'Ger's planet…
一个住了很多活机器的行星
A planet populated by living machines…
不可思议的科技
Unbelievable technology…
威者拥有跨越这个宇宙的知识
V'Ger has knowledge that spans this universe…
但是，以它所有的纯逻辑来说…
And yet, with all its pure logic…
威者是荒芜、 冰冷的
V'Ger is barren. Cold…
没有神秘的动物
No mystery…
没有美感
No beauty…
我早该知道
I should have… known…
知道？知道什么？
Known? Known what?
你早该知道什么？
What should you have known?
这种简单的感觉…
This simple feeling…
威者是无法领会的
…is beyond V'Ger's comprehension…
没有意义，没有希望
No meaning. No hope…
没有答案
No answers…
它在发问
It's asking questions…
「我是否…就是这样？」
"Is this… all that I am?"
「还有别的吗？」
"Is there nothing more?"
驾驶室叫队长
Bridge to Captain…
我是葛克
Kirk here…
星际舰队发出微弱讯号
A faint signal from Starfleet, sir…
入侵者星云在监视器上27分钟了
Intruder cloud has been located on the monitors for 27 minutes…
星云在靠近时迅速消散
Cloud dissipating rapidly as it approaches…
星际舰队说速度减至负翘曲度
Starfleet reports velocity is slowed to subwarp speed…
我们距离地球轨道三分钟
We are three minutes from Earth orbit…
我马上来
I'll be right there…
我要冼朴到驾驶室
I need Spock on the bridge…
5c.c.德拉菲素
Dalaphaline, five ccs…
机器…发射机器到地球上
A machine planet sending a machine to Earth,
寻找创制者，实在难以置信
Looking for its Creator. It's absolutely incredible.
星际舰队发放这个威者位置图
Starfleet is sending this tactical on V'Ger's position…
航空在传送一个讯号
V'Ger is transmitting a signal…
占！
Jim!
从威者发来的
From V'Ger…
威者向创造者发出讯号
V'Ger signals the Creator…
一种由载波传送的三进制代码
A simple binary code, transmitted by carrier-wave signal…
无线电
Radio…
无线电？
Radio?
占，威者要一个答案
Jim, V'Ger expects an answer…
答案？我不知问题是什么
An answer? I don't know the question…
创造者没有回应
The Creator has not responded…
所有行星防御系统都失灵了
All planetary defence systems have just gone inoperative…
星际舰队说那些装置…
Starfleet says the devices are proceeding…
准备以等距位置环绕这个行星
To equidistant positions orbiting the planet!
是撞击我们的那些东西
The same things that hit us…
它们的威力强几百倍的
They are hundreds of times more powerful…
它们可从那些位置摧毁整个行星
From those positions, they could devastate the entire planet…
为什么？
Why?
创造者没有回答
The Creator has not answered…
要从这个行星消除碳化组件侵扰
The carbon-unit infestation is to be removed from the planet…
- 为什么？- 你们侵扰企业号
- Why? - You infest Enterprise…
你们同样干扰着创造者
You interfere with the Creator in the same manner…
机器！
Machine!
队长
Captain…
威者是个小孩，你该这样对待她
V'Ger is a child. I suggest you treat her as such…
- 小孩？- 对，队长，小孩
- A child? - Yes, Captain. A child…
进化、 学习、 搜寻
Evolving, learning, searching…
- 本能地有需要 - 需要什么？
- Instinctively needing. - Needing what?
这小孩快摧毁地球所有生物了
Spock! This child is about to wipe out every living thing on Earth!
你提议我们怎办？打它的屁股？
What do you suggest we do? Spank it?
它只知道它有需要
It knows only that it needs, Commander…
但像我们一样，不知道需要什么
But, like so many of us, it does not know what…
碳化组件知道为何创造者没回应
The carbon units know why the Creator has not responded…
快说出资料
Disclose the information…
威者再撤销环绕第三行星的装置
Not until V'Ger withdraws the devices orbiting the third planet…
队长！
Captain!
接收不到星际舰了！威者干扰
I'm losing Starfleet! Interference from V'Ger…
葛克组件，快说出资料
Kirk unit, disclose the information…
为何创造者没有回应？
Why has the Creator not responded?
不说
No…
保护所有岗位，撤离驾驶室
Secure all stations. Clear the bridge…
撤离驾驶室？
Clear the bridge, Captain?
这是命令，撤离驾驶室
That was the order. Clear the bridge…
你的小孩发脾气了，冼朴先生
Your child is having a tantrum, Mr Spock…
威者要那个资料
V'Ger requires the information…
驾驶室！保护所有岗位，快走
Bridge! Secure all stations. Move out…
占，这到底是什么策略？
Jim, what the hell kind of strategy is this?
飞船转为自动操作
Ship's functions going to automatic…
威者摧毁企业号，资料也被摧毁
If V'Ger destroys the Enterprise, the information will be destroyed…
拒给所需资料是合逻辑的
It is illogical to withhold required information…
葛克组件！
Kirk unit!
为何你不说出资料？
Why do you not disclose information?
威者会摧毁第三行星的碳化组件
V'Ger will destroy the carbon units on the third planet…
他们镇压创造者
They repressed the Creator…
我不会说出资料的
The information will not be disclosed!
威者需要那些资料
V'Ger needs the information…
那么威者要先撤销那些环绕装置
Then V'Ger must withdraw all the orbiting devices…
若碳化组件说出资料，威者同意
V'Ger will comply, if the carbon units will disclose the information…
它学得很快，是不是？
It learns fast, doesn't it?
队长，那艘飞船，威者…
Captain, the vessel, V'Ger…
很明显是从一个中央脑体运作
Obviously operates from a central brain complex…
那些环绕装置是从那个点控制
The orbiting devices are controlled from that point…
对了
Precisely…
不能把资料说给威者的探测器
The information cannot be disclosed to V'Ger's probe…
只可直接告诉威者
But only to V'Ger, directly…
- 前进，队长 - 光束
- Forward motion, Captain. - Tractor beam…
队长，下一步怎样？
Captain, what's the next move?
问题是，有没有下一步？
The question is, Mr Decker, is there a next move?
返回工作岗位
Resume duty stations…
所有人员返回岗位
All personnel, resume stations…
迪克先生，看来我的吹牛奏效了
Well, Mr Decker, it seems my bIuff has been called…
恐怕我们胜算不大
I'm afraid our hand is weak, Captain…
那些装置几时到达最后位置？
Mr Chekov, when do those devices reach final position?
二十七分钟，确定
27 minutes. Mark…
队长，我相信那是我们的目的地
Captain, I believe that is our destination…
企业号外形成了一股氧气引力罩
An oxygen gravity envelope is forming outside the Enterprise…
停下来了，队长
Forward motion stopped, Captain…
威者
V'Ger…
我找到威者的无线电讯号来源了
Sir, I've located the source of V'Ger's radio signal…
就在前面
It's directly ahead…
那发射器是威者和创造者的联系
That transmitter is a vital link between V'Ger and its Creator…
碳化组件现在给威者说出资料
The carbon units will now provide V'Ger with the required information…
迪克先生，我每隔五分钟联络你
Mr Decker. I will contact you every five minutes…
队长
Captain…
我想跟你一起去
I'd like to go along…
苏洛先生，你暂代指挥
Mr Sulu, you have the conn…
威者
V'Ger…
V-G-E-R…
威者
V'Ger…
航海家号
V-O-Y-A-G-E-R…
航海家号！
Voyager!
航海家六号？
Voyager VI?
太空总署
NASA. National Aeronautics and Space Administration…
占，这是三百年前发射的
Jim, this was launched more than 300 years ago…
航海家号系列
Voyager series…
负责收集资料和把它传送回地球
Designed to collect data, and transmit it back to Earth…
队长！
Captain!
航海家六号消失在黑洞中
Voyager VI disappeared into what they used to call a black hole…
它一定是出现在银河系的另一边
It must have emerged on the far side of the galaxy…
再掉进这机械行星的引力场
And fell into the machine planet's gravitational field…
那些机械居民以为是它们的同类
The machine inhabiters found it to be one of their own kind…
原始但类似
Primitive yet kindred…
他们发现它简单的二十世纪程式
They discovered its simple 20th-century programming…
收集所有的资料
Collect all data possible…
尽量学习它
Learn all that is learnable…
把那些资料送返它的创造者
Return that information to its Creator…
正确，迪克先生
Precisely, Mr Decker…
那些机器把它逐字解读
The machines interpreted it literally…
制造这飞船让航海家号完成程式
They built this entire vessel so Voyager could fulfil its programming…
而在它的回程中
And on its journey back…
它积累了大量知识
It amassed so much knowledge…
自己达致有意识
It achieved consciousness itself…
成为了一个生物
It became a living thing…
葛克组件，威者等着那些资料
Kirk unit. V'Ger awaits the information…
企业号，在船上电脑记录图书馆
Enterprise, order up the ship's computer library of records…
翻查20世纪太空总署航海家六号
On the late 20th-century NASA probe, Voyager VI…
我们要那套太空总署
We want the old NASA code signal…
指示探测器传送资料的旧讯号码
That instructs the probe to transmit its data…
- 乌拉，快点！- 是，长官
- And fast, Uhura! - Aye, sir…
它发出准备传送资料的讯号了
It's been signalling its readiness to transmit its information…
地球没有人懂得旧讯号和回应
No one on Earth could recognise the old signal and respond…
创造者没有回答
The Creator does not answer…
威者
V'Ger…
我们就是创造者
We are the Creator…
不合逻辑，碳组件不是真生物
That is not logical. Carbon units are not true life forms…
我们会证明它的
We will prove it…
它们会让你可以完成你的程式
We will make it possible for you to complete your programming…
只有创造者可以做得到
Only the Creator could accomplish that…
企业号
Enterprise…
我们刚收到那套回应代码
We have just received the response code…
把企业号发射器调校至合适频率
Set the Enterprise transmitter on appropriate frequency…
立刻传送那套代码
And transmit the code now…
传送中
Transmitting…
最后的列数是…
And the final sequence…
那该可以启动航海家号的发射器
That should trigger Voyager's transmitter…
航海家号没有传送它的资料
Voyager is not transmitting its data, Captain…
创造者要跟威者结合
The Creator must join with V'Ger…
乌拉，重复最后的列数
Uhura, repeat the final sequence…
创造者要跟威者结合
The Creator must join with V'Ger…
航海家号没有传送
Voyager is not transmitting…
因为它接收不到最后的列数
Because it did not receive the final sequence…
我们剩下十分钟
We're down to ten minutes…
企业号，准备
Enterprise, stand by…
- 天线引线溶了 - 刚被威者溶掉
- The antenna leads are melted away. - Yes, just now. By V'Ger itself…
为什么？
Why?
- 防止接收 - 当然
- To prevent reception. - Of course…
要把创造者带来，完成传送代码
To bring the Creator here. To finish transmitting the code in person…
为了接触创造者
To touch the Creator…
捕捉神？威者会大失所望
Capture God? V'Ger's in for one hell of a disappointment…
或者不会
Perhaps not, Doctor…
队长
Captain…
威者一定要进化
V'Ger must evolve…
它的知识已达到这个宇宙的极限
Its knowledge has reached the limits of this universe…
它需要的是它的问题的答案
What it requires is the answer to its question…
「还有别的吗？」
"Is there nothing more?"
宇宙之外还有什么？
What more is there than the universe?
其他的空间，生物状态
Other dimensions, levels of being…
它们的存在不能被逻辑性地证明
Whose existence cannot be proven logically…
所以威者不能相信它们
Therefore, V'Ger is incapable of believing in them…
威者需要人类的品质才能进化
What V'Ger needs in order to evolve is a human quality…
我们超越逻辑的能力
Our capacity to leap beyond logic…
跟它的创造者结合就可以做到
Joining with its Creator might accomplish that…
这副机器要亲身跟一个人类结合
This machine wants to physically join with a human?
可行吗？
Is that possible?
我们试试看
Let's find out.
我会经地面测试电脑输入列数
I'll key the sequence through the ground-test computer…
你不知道会有什么后果
You don't know what that'll do!
我知道，医生
Yes, I do, Doctor…
迪克，不要！
Decker, don't!
占，像想要企业号般，我要这个
Jim, I want this. As much as you wanted the Enterprise, I want this…
队长
Captain…
冼朴！我们是否看见新生物诞生
Spock! Did we just see the beginning of a new life form?
是的，我们见证了一次诞生
Yes, Captain. We witnessed a birth…
它可能是我们进化过程的下一步
Possibly a next step in our evolution…
我怀疑…
I wonder…
我很久没有接生婴儿了
It's been a long time since I delivered a baby…
- 希望它有个好开始 - 但愿如此
- I hope it got off to a good start. - I hope so, too…
我们给了它创造自己目标的能力
I think we gave it the ability to create its own sense of purpose…
凭我们人类的弱点…
Out of our own human weaknesses…
和克服它们的精神而达成
And the drive that compels us to overcome them…
还有很多愚蠢的人类感情，是吗
And a lot of foolish human emotions, right, Mr Spock?
是的，可惜它也要应付它们
Quite true, Doctor. Unfortunately, it will have to deal with them as well…
星际舰队要求损毁和受伤报告
Starfleet request damage and injury reports and vessel status…
报告有两人受伤
Report two casualties…
伊莉亚中尉，迪克队长
It Ilia. Capt Decker…
是，长官
Aye, sir…
更正，他们不是受伤，他们是…
Correction. They're not casualties. They are…
把他们列为失踪吧
List them as missing…
- 飞船运作完全正常 - 是，长官
- Vessel status fully operational. - Aye, sir…
史葛先生！
Mr Scott!
我们可要给企业号一次彻底试航
Shall we give the Enterprise a proper shakedown?
是时候那样做了，长官
I would say it's time for that, sir…
我们可在四天内送你去火神星
We can have you on Vulcan in four days, Mr Spock…
不用了，我在火神星的任务已完
Unnecessary, Mr Scott. My task on Vulcan is completed…
苏洛先生？翘曲度一级前进
Mr Sulu? Ahead warp one…
翘曲度一级
Warp one, sir…
去哪里，长官？
Heading, sir?
外面
Out there…
那边
Thataway.
（人类的冒险之旅才刚开始）